Thomas Seropian

French & Lebanese dual nationalities
Currently based in London, United Kingdom

+44 74 2362 9937 thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

Technical Lead / Senior Software Engineer

Skillset

Managing web applications and technical team for an international online media publisher. Software engineering. Team recruitment and management. Agile delivery. Web applications design and development. System architecture, testing and hosting. Leadership, communication with technical and non-technical audiences. Strong sense of innovation. Design and creation of user stories. Research, prototyping. Group training and capacity building. Creativity. Flexibility. Project management. Hiring, mentoring and performance management. Establishment and management of a team of 4 technologists in London for an international NGO.

Work experience

Technical Lead for an international online media publishing group **Jamie Oliver Limited**, London, United Kingdom – February 2017 to present (www.jamieoliver.com)

→ Responsible for infrastructure and web applications supporting Jamie's online presence.

Designing, defining roadmaps, scoping and delivering new features and APIs for jamieoliver.com and other departments of the business. Hands-on development of key backend features such as migrating the signup journey towards an API driven process. Integration with Salesforce.com. Managing legacy code base.

Managing AWS based infrastructure, including release processes, optimisations and improvements.

Leading technical team (both in house and freelancers), sourcing and hiring, on-boarding, day to day management, code reviews and mentoring. Organising backlog and sprints. Managing third party providers. Liaising with Internal stakeholders (project managers, product owners, business managers).

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS (EC2, RDS, SQS, Elasticache, Route53, IAM, S3), Laravel, RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Javascript, Node.js, Vue.js, WordPress, Ansible, CentOS, Apache, Nginx, Varnish, Jira, Vagrant

Technology Manager for an international NGO **Internews** London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (www.internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development and delivery of innovation and technology components

 Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local media start-ups among the most repressive regimes.

 Leading on delivering full service of websites and news publishing apps from design to deployment and hosting. Hands-on control, testing and reviewing. Ensuring a security first approach. Prototyping.

 Managing and monitoring activities' budgets. Designing rapid response to urgent needs for support from the field.
- → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

 Overseeing recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 4 technologists (2 developers, 1 coordinator and 1 helpdesk officer). Ensuring planning, coordination and distribution of work, setting priorities, agreeing detailed work plans, budgets and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Performance management. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap. Strong focus on scalability, quality & security.
- → Strategic Development

 Proposal planning and writing. Improving quality of development processes (including specification, operations, testing, deployment, policy writing...). Speaking at conferences and events
- → <u>Technology:</u> Wordpress, Drupal (7/8), Bootstrap, Laravel, Javascript, HTML5, NodeJS, Wordpress, RESTful APIs, Cloud hosting (Public / Private), Ansible, Drush, Ubuntu, MySQL, Nginx, OpenVPN, GPG encryption

Freelance Consultant in open source technologies

Self-Employed London, United Kingdom – April 2014 to September 2015 (www.seropian.io)

- → Designing & developing web applications and prototypes for various range of clients
- → Areas of work: Drupal, E-Commerce, ERP web applications, Infrastructure management.

Designed and built a subscription-based application, including automated online payments. Agile Prototyping. Developed Intranet and extranet applications including import/export modules for a booking agent. Defined and prioritized user stories in close collaboration with different team members.

→ Technology: Drupal 7 (Custom Modules development), Drush, Github, Selenium HQ, Vagrant, RESTful APIs

ICT Projects Manager / Web Application Engineer for an international NGO Internews Europe Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - March 2009 to March 2014 (www.internews.eu)

→ On-line freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications, custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Managing localizations, training & support

Writing user stories & specifications. Managing external contractors and developers, resources & infrastructures: Deployment and monitoring of servers, secure hosting & video platforms. Building, delivering and facilitating trainings & trainers on ICT topics. Training of trainers on website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA)

→ <u>Technology</u>: Drupal, Mediawiki, XML/JSON, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Collectd, Vagrant, Nginx

Software Engineer for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (www.hellotipi.com)

 \rightarrow Designed, developed and implemented new features for the service.

Video sharing. Photo tagging. Revamped registration process. Multilingual support. Managed client support.

→ Technology: Debian/Apache/MySQL/PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg.

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer trainings in youth training centres. Developed activities in 2 major cities. Managed recruitment of local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs. Participated to feasibility studies & design for countrywide projects.

Assistant Manager for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (www.valeo.com)

Designed & implemented tools for course supports creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

Education

MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (www.esiea.fr).

 \rightarrow Graduated with first class honours.

Foreign languages

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner